M@X @ Hon3yHD
(GUNSHOTS)
Last night, I dreamt I could
shoot like you. (CHUCKLES)
That's why we're here.
It's a good skill to have.
It's just
so heavy. Sorry.
They're making them lighter now.
I'll get one for you.
(INHALES SHARPLY)
Now,
squeezethetflggen
Justsqueezeit Charlotte. lam.
You're going to have
to squeeze it harder.
But I'm squeezing it.
Whoo! (CHUCKLES)
I pulled the trigger
at least.
You were aiming
for the tins.
You really need to be prepared
for life out here, darling.
I am prepared.
I pulled the trigger.
(GUNSHOTS IN DISTANCE)
(GUNSHOTS)
Oh, Betty, I hate guns.
A nice sweet tea, ma'am?
Yes, thank you.
(CHICKEN SQUAWKS)
(PIANO PLAYING)
Thank you. Betty, when a lady
perspires, she uses a handkerchief.
Thank you, ma'am.
(CONTINUES PLAYING PIANO)
So, he says, "Why wasn't
Jesus born in New Zealand?"
And the other chap says,
"Because they couldn't find
three wise men and a virgin."
(ALL LAUGHING)
So, Charlotte,
how are you settling in?
She's doing superbly.
I know it'll take time.
It's a beautiful island,
but it's just...
Different.
Oxfordshire, yes?
DAVID: But born in London.
Dieu. That place
would spoil anyone.
My wife knows how much
this farm means to me.
It's been a long time coming
and a dream come true.
Well, my husband can
talk rne into anything.
MR. JONES: You'll get used to
it soon enough. My Myfanwy did.
(CHUCKLES)
When I saw my first weta
bug, I thought it was a cat.
What's a weta bug?
MR. JONES: Not to mention
the natives.
Who are not as
frightening astheylook.
No, but if they look
Hkethetype that could eat you,
then more than likely,
they are.
MRS. JONES:
Oh, George, please.
MR. JONES: Well,
Charlotte needn't worry.
I mean, look at her. Not nearly
enough meat on her bones.
And how far along
are you?
(CHUCKLES)
Will the grounds be finished
before the baby's born?
That's the plan.
So, it will just be
the three of us.
No more farmhands.
Hello, you beautiful baby.
Could you please just stay in
there for a wee while longer,
all nice and warm,
until we get the roof on? And
then the house is all yours.
How about that?
(HUMMING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Oh! Oh! Oh!
David! Oh! David!
DAVID: Coming!
Charlotte!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(BABY CRYING)
(DOOR OPENS)
(FOOTSTEPS)
(BABY FUSSING)
MAN: Drop your gun.
(GASPS)
MAN: Back over there!
CHARLOTTE: David, don't...
Darling, just stay calm.
CHARLOTTE: Arthur.
DAVID: Please.
Move over there.
(ARTHUR FUSSING)
CHARLOTTE: Please,
don't hurt my son.
MAN: Back over there.
(ARTHUR FUSSING)
CHARLOTTE: Arthur, darling.
Now, the safe.
We don't have a safe.
(GUN CLICKS) All right, just please...
Just... Please...
Why are you doing this?
After I helped you.
MAN: Everything in it.
DAVID: I gave you work
when you needed it.
MAN: Everything!
That is everything.
A roof over your head.
Food from our stove.
MAN: Shut your mouth now.
Back to bed.
Back!
If either of youse leave this
room, your boy is for the worms.
Am I understood?
(GROANS)
(ARTHUR CRYING)
Charlotte.
Go.
(ARTHUR CRYING)
POLICEMAN: And you say
he worked for you?
Why do they keep asking the same questions?
This is madness.
My husband would
take in strays.
He always said that he was
willing to help anyone
who would work an honest day, so, yes.
He knew him.
They all knew him.
Will you find my son?
Well, it's a, uh... It's a lot
of land to cover, Mrs. Lockton.
We'll do our best.
If my husband knew him, then
you must have known him, too.
I've seen how
you've befriended
each and every one of them
that came through.
Ma'am, I didn't. I swear.
They were your friends.
I was only being welcoming like Mr.
Lockton would have wanted.
Tell me who it was.
Ma'am...
(SHOUTS) Look at me!
Tell me who it was!
I don't know who it was.
I didn't seem him up close.
Then pack your bags. Now!
Ma'am, please.
POLICEMAN: Ma'am,
it's been three months.
And we're sorry, Mrs. Lockton.
We've looked high and low.
We've combed
the entire district.
My advice is, it's...
It's time to move on.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Mrs. Lockton?
Yes.
From the post office.
(GASPS)
Oh...
Rider, wait!
Wait.
Ma'am?
"Your son is alive and well.
Your son is alive.
"If you want
to see him again,
"place £500 in the Bank of
New Zealand by Friday next,
"to the account set up
in your husband's name.
"Attempt to trace the money
or go to the police,
"and you will never
see your son again."
When was this
delivered to you?
Three days ago.
From where?
Pass me
the envelope, ma'am.
This was launched in Corktown.
South of here.
About half a days away.
How would I get there?
There's a train
from Little Hills.
But Corktown, Mrs. Lockton.
Will you be traveling alone?
Yes. And as soon as I can.
(HORN BLOWING)
(HORN BLARING)
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Excuse me,
where's the post office?
It's just there.
(CHARLOTTE CLEARS THROAT)
Can I help you, miss?
This was posted
from here, I believe.
I believe it would
have been, yes.
Did it originate here?
Not so sure
about that, miss.
So, it might have been
shipped from somewhere else?
May well have done
exactly that, yes.
Where? No idea. This town
is the end of the line.
The other side
of those hills,
people are scattered every
which way for days on end.
Sorry I couldn't be
of more help.
Where might I find
the Bank of New Zealand?
Well, you're looking
at it.
I'm the closest thing you'll
find this far from Nelson.
Do you hold an account
in the name of "Lockton"?
Lockton? Lockton.
Looks like I can
finally help you today.
Goldtown Hotel? All those
accounts are held there?
Goldtown Hotel.
Aye.
Diggers' money.
It's held at the hotel
before it gets sent to bank.
Can I get there
from here?
If you're willing to travel for a week.
Maybe more.
Only way through
is that mountain, see?
Plenty of lunatics heading over
that way, chasing their fortune.
Plenty heading back, too. They're
starving to death, they are.
But I can get over there,
from here?
Ask the Fréulein. She'll know
when there's a party heading out.
Across the street there.
No journey
for a lady, miss.
If you don't mind
my saying so.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Looks like we just picked
the wrong time to leave.
Don't you mind me, missy.
I'll see you later.
I'll even pay you extra if you
keep that pretty little hat on.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(JINGLES)
CHARLOTTE: I'm looking
for the Fréulein.
Are you working?
No. Are you the Fréulein?
No. Right.
Come on, then.
No. Wait.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
(GROANS)
(CHEERING)
I was told there might be some
gentlemen heading to Goldtown.
Gentlemen? (CHUCKLES)
There are none of those here.
You're a digger?
No.
Then only one other thing
you can be.
And if you are,
you and me need a deal.
No woman in Goldtown makes
money without deal with me.
I'm not a digger,
nor anything else.
I just want to get to
Goldtown for my own reasons.
Ten pounds.
To get to Goldtown?
Bully.
Tell Bully where you go.
Excuse me?
The Fréulein says you're
heading to Goldtown.
Aye. In the morning.
Taking supplies.
Girls, too.
Well, I'd like to
come along.
Would you?
I've paid her
to get there.
No, you haven't.
You paw Fraulein
to get to me.
So, to get to Goldtown?
Can you do that?
Or even that?
Everything will be fine.
Everything will be fine. (LAUGHS)
No.
No. I can't.
But...
I can do this.
Fifty.
You know, you shouldn't be flashing
your jewelry around like that.
Not in a place
like this.
And, uh, you've
just been fleeced.
Not if you take me
to Goldtown.
(CHUCKLES)
(MUSIC PLAYING IN DISTANCE)
(INSTINCT CHATTER IN DISTANCE)
You still coming?
That's what we discussed.
See any whores
on your way out?
When you're ready,
you're in that one.
Thank you.
Easier without this, miss.
WOMAN: Thank you, ladies. I'll have a look.
Thanks. Good luck.
One day, we're gonna vote.
Women are gonna vote, and two fingers
to anyone who tries to stop us.
You'll still be
a two-bit whore.
Aye. A two-bit whore
with a vote, though.
(LAUGHING)
Jesus. Two weeks
inthatshflbox?
You really know how to
make a girl feel special.
Silk.
(MEN CONVERSING
IN OTHER LANGUAGE)
So, you're a dancer?
Shelook
like a bloody dancer?
Never turned a trick
neither, I bet.
What's your name?
Charlotte.
That's a pretty name.
I'm Heather.
That's Flamenco.
Well, we call her Flamenco.
What's your
real name, again?
Maria Theresa
Angelica Evita Pasimos.
(LAUGHS) Flamenco.
What are you
doing here?
There's plenty of people
who need Goldt0wn's money
more than the likes
of you.
What would you know
about the likes of me?
You're a snotty bitch,
that much I do know.
That's Honey.
What do you think you're doing?
Those are mine.
I asked you what do you think you're doing?
Those are my shoes.
Looks to me like
you've got plenty.
You have no right to steal.
So, take them back.
Go ahead.
Vamos. Take them off me.
(CHUCKLES)
There.
It's a matching set.
If you're feeling generous,
I'll take the petticoat.
Thafs“.
CHARLOTTE: You will give me
back what's mine on my demand!
(SPEAKS SPANISH) (IN
ENGLISH) You stole my money.
(GUNSHOT)
Ladies, ladies,
first night.
She stole my money.
I take her shoes.
My shoes and my money.
Is it in there?
No, but she's wearing
my shoes,
so she must have
taken my money.
(SHOES THUD)
Someone else must have
taken it, then.
Aye, so now you're
accusing the rest of us?
No, but all the money
I had in that bag is gone.
Would that be the stash that you
were flashing around last night?
Like it was everyone else's
but your own?
You stayed the night
at Madam Fréulein's.
The moment you closed
your eyes,
you waved goodbye to
everything you own.
Just be thankful we're going
to Goldtown, princess.
You wouldn't believe what some will
pay to see you flash your titties.
We should bury him.
HUNTER: Waste of time.
Birds gotta eat,
same as worms.
We're moving on.
(CONVERSING IN OTHER LANGUAGE)
(GUNSHOT)
(WOMEN SCREAMING)
(YELLS)
(WHIMPERING)
MAN: Move it!
HEATHER:
Go, go, go, go, go!
(SCREAMING)
(WOMEN SCREAMING)
Let's make this easy,
eh, fellas?
All we want is the food.
And the whiskey.
Maybe these lasses
for the ride.
And we'll be on our way.
It's not gonna happen, pal.
Then you've just come
to the end of the line, pal.
(MAN GRUNTS)
(GUNSHOTS)
(CHARLOTTE WHIMPERING)
(GUNSHOT)
(GASPS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(CHANTING IN OTHER LANGUAGE)
(GUNSHOT)
(COUGHING)
You might
want to look away.
(GUNSHOT)
(COUGHS)
(WHIMPERING)
(WOMEN SCATTING)
You've got the wrong leg.
(ALL LAUGHING)
And then what
at the end?
To finish!
(LAUGHING CONTINUES)
HEATHER: We'll practice, okay?
Come on, princess.
Let your hair down for once in your life.
You're alive.
(SPEAKS OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH)
Do you mind?
I would like that.
There must be something
special in Goldtown
for a lady like you to do
something like this.
My son, he was stolen by the
man who killed my husband.
And you think
he's in Goldtown?
You know who he is? The man? No.
If you start knocking on doors,
you see, word will spread fast.
So, you need to
move faster.
Do you live there
in Goldtown?
We work for the boss,
but we're not diggers.
So, say you, uh,
find this boy.
I will find my son.
Then what?
I was gonna pay him.
The man.
You think it
would be that simple,
after he killed
your husband?
Well, it'll be 1 O times
less simple without money.
I don't know.
I will steal him back.
You got a gun?
Do you even know
how to shoot it?
(WHISPERS) In the name
of the wee man...
(CHUCKLES)
Well, we're still
a week away.
We'll have to do
something about it.
Thank you.
Don't thank me. Not till the
boy is back in your arms.
And for what it's worth,
what you just told me there, you
shouldn't have told me any of that.
Not a single word.
Because you don't know
who I am.
Yes, I do.
You saved my life.
Even someone who
saves your life, princess.
You don't tell them
stuff like that, okay?
(WOMEN LAUGHING)
Now, make some friends.
Christ's sake, you're gonna
need them where we're going.
BULLY: We're a man down.
You gotta know you can
defend yourselves. Again.
(GUNSHOTS)
You can act fast.
He's not gonna stand there,
waiting for you to aim.
So,shoot your bloody guns.
(GUNSHOTS)
(SPEAKS SPANISH)
Oh, well, at least one
of you will live. Again.
You're thinking too much.
Come on. Again.
(GUNSHOTS)
I'm gonna count to 10.
One, two, three...
When you gotta shoot, shoot.
Don't think.
(GUNSHOT)
Reload. Again.
(GUNSHOTS)
(GUNSHOT)
Whoa, whoa, whoa!
Come on!
Come on. Come on! Come on!
(HUNTER SHOUTS)
What the... Come on.
Let's get a move on.
It's not the river.
It's the wagon.
BULLY: Matai, Klaus,
come fix the wagon.
Right. Everyone out.
Why?
Because we're stopping here.
BULLY: Move your asses.
Come on.
Don't tell me there ain't an easier
way to get to Goldtown than this.
It's the axle, boss.
We'll figure it out.
It's busted.
Hunter, we'll figure it out.
What's that on her neck?
It's a tattoo.
CHARLOTTE: A tattoo of what?
Prison.
She spent six years
as a maid,
but being told what to do
her whole life
sentherspflflng
in the master's food.
And a lot else besides.
Locked up for three years.
CHARLOTTE: Was Flamenco
in prison, too?
Nah. Shipwreck, or some such.
She survived,
but her family didn't.
Pretty girl Hkethatthough.
She can make her way.
If she can stomach
what it takes.
And you?
BULLYI Pull!
(GRUNTING)
Got it?
Yeah.
(GRUNTING)
BULLY: Feed it in there.
Hold on. One second.
(GRUNTING)
Come on, lift it!
Put your back in it, man!
That's it!
(GROANS)
Hey!
Hey! Hey!
It's the axle!
It's pinning him down!
Step on the axle! Lift it! Lift that up!
Lift it up! Get it off him!
Come on!
Get it up, the axle!
One, two, three! Go! Pull!
(CRYING) Please! No!
(INDISTINCT SHOUTING)
Come on! Get this stuff off!
Hurry up, hurry up!
Help him, please, somebody!
Lift! Lift, man!
I can't lift it, Bully!
Come on, come on, get it off! Come on!
Clear that stuff! Come on!
Come on!
Come on, man!
One, two, three, go!
Come on! Come on, man!
(MATAI SINGING
IN OTHER LANGUAGE)
We get the wagon loaded with whatever
we can manage, and we move on.
We're never gonna make it.
So, what are you suggesting
we do instead, sweetheart?
Turn back.
Get home alive, at least.
You saying I can't
get us there?
Are you saying you can?
Fine. Turn back. (SPITS) I'll
bury you on the way back.
I need to get to Goldtown.
There's no point
in arriving dead.
I'll show you dead, bitch!
You want to see dead? I'll give you dead!
KLAUS: Hunter!
Hunter!
Leave her be.
Ah!
All right.
We make the wagon good,
we move on,
and we camp by dark.
See, here's the thing.
You don't look like a whore.
(SNIFFING) Mmm.
You don't smell
like a whore.
I wonder what you do do
FLAMENCO". Hola, Guapo.
(IN ENGLISH)
Thought I your sefiorita.
Vamos, mi amor.
(CONTINUES SPEAKING SPANISH)
Thank you.
Honey told me
you lost your family.
I lost mine, too.
No talk of family.
They're here, boys!
The girls are here!
(MEN HOOTING AND WHISTLING)
(MEN CHEERING)
(LAUGHING)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
HEATHER: Wh00!
(CHEERING CONTINUES)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
My case is in there, love.
Nice-looking boy.
Have you had a bath?
Oh, then you might need
another one.
Bertie! They're here!
The lasses are here!
(ALL CHEERING)
Well, ladies, ladies, ladies.
Welcome, welcome.
Well, well, well.
What a divine selection.
I'm Bertie Russell.
At your attendance.
I trust yourjourney
treated you well?
No. It was shit.
Oh. Well, let's hope
that your stay with us
proves to be
just the opposite.
Delightful, in fact.
And fruitful to us all.
Uh, Mr. McCullen has
a meeting at West Port,
so, uh, it's my honorable duty to escort
you to, uh... Well, your boudoirs.
Ah, an English rose. I like it.
You're gonna go down a treat.
All right, gentlemen.
Give the ladies
time to freshen up,
and after that, you can throw all
your money and yourselves at them.
Soon, all this will be
out of here,
and we'll have more rooms
for more girlies.
This is just
the beginning.
HEATHER: Look at
our stage, ladies.
Drapes will make it nice.
RUSSELL: Yeah.
Aye. A touch of class.
Now, where's the English rose?
Ah, there you are.
(SINGING) She were just The sort of
creature, boys That nature did intend
To walk around the world Me
boys Without the Grecian Bend
And did she wear a chignon
I'll have you all to know
That I met her in the garden
Where the praties grow
Right. I'll be doing the
negotiating on your behalf.
Make sure you're well kept,
safe, and well fed.
And all for a mere
35% of your takings.
Wait. Are you the boss?
No. Mr. McCullen
is the boss.
Aye. Then it's Mr. McCullen
we work for.
As do I.
It's his 35%, not mine.
20%, or I glue
my bloomers to me arse.
Well, perhaps we could come to some
kind of quid pro quo arrangement.
Just show us the rooms,
you dirty little bastard.
RUSSELL: It's good to have a
friend sometimes, you know.
HEATHER: Aye, it depends
on the friend.
RUSSELL: Right.
Onwards and upwards.
HEATHER: This is just
like the big house.
HONEY: How many
bloody stairs?
(CHUCKLES)
Here's where you'll be providing
your fleshy pleasures.
And over here,
yet another little
love grotto
from which to sing
your siren songs.
And over here,
we have the grand suite.
And the last
but not the least,
the not-so-grand suite.
Very funny.
(HEATHER LAUGHS)
HEATHER: Hey, what happened
to the dresses?
We were promised
good dresses.
If Mr. Mc:Cullen gave his
word, he'll keep his word.
Right. I'm gonna
leave you lovely ladies
to make yourselves
evenlovehen
You won't be shy of work
tonight, that's for certain.
Oh, shit.
Won't be making anything
looking like this.
They never leave you,
do they?
She was three.
(SNIFFLING)
Gentlemen! Both the drink
and the ladies
await your
unbridled appreciation.
(MEN CHEERING)
Well, it appears there are some
things more desirable than gold.
HEATHER: Hello.
(CHUCKUNG)
So pleased
to meet you all.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Buy me a drink?
HEATHER: I'm so excited!
(LAUGHING)
Thank you. Thank you.
So who's gonna help me?
Oh. Sorry.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Ooh! Sorry.
Look at you.
Sorry?
Polite thought.
No.
Are you for sale? All right. No!
Stop it!
MAN: I'll give you
good money.
Look at you. Stay with me.
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
Are you leaving?
Job's done, miss.
I wanted to say thank you.
You be safe, now.
Are you leaving, too?
This is not my home.
I never asked your name.
Matai.
How often do you come
to Goldtown, Matai?
When somebody needs
to get over the mountain.
And say somebody did.
Already you don't like it?
It's not my home, either. I was
never planning on staying.
And I'll need help leaving.
I can return.
I don't know
how long I'll need.
Are you in trouble,
Miss Charlotte?
I can be back
in three days.
Three days. Yes.
Thank you, three days.
Hello.
(BABY CRYING)
Aw. (GASPS)
(GUN COCKS)
Give reason
I don't pull trigger.
(BABY FUSSING)
I'm sorry. I heard crying,
andlthought the baby was sick.
No sick.
No. I'm sorry.
(WOMAN SPEAKS
OTHER LANGUAGE)
Are there any
other families here?
You go now! You no come again!
(SPEAKS OTHER LANGUAGE)
Who took that portrait?
Who took that picture?
MAN: I say go! 'Cause I
have the same picture.
I have the same picture!
I'm going! I'm going!
I'm going!
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Oh, there you are. lthought
you might be upstairs,
earning yourself
some money.
There's a lot of the fellows want
a taste of your wares, darling.
Listen. Walk with me.
Gentlemen.
If you want a bed,
a nice roof over your head,
lovely fires to keep you warm,
then you do what the other girlies
are doing that you rode in with.
Either up there on the stage
or flat on your back.
Because it's either that,
or you're out the door,
and you don't come back.
That's how it works.
Show's in an hour.
Did you see their faces?
Theylookloaded.
CHARLOTTE: Very nice.
Is there a dress I can wear?
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(MEN CHEERING)
(LAUGHING)
(MEN HOOTING)
MAN: Come on, girls!
(MEN CONTINUES CHEERING)
(INAUDIBLE)
(MEN CHEERING)
Marry me!
Which one of us?
Any of you! All of you!
(ALL LAUGHING)
Oh, Mr. Mc:Cullen. We weren't
expecting you back tonight.
How went your day?
Good, Bertie.
Thank you.
So, uh, all this is yours, the hotel?
You got a wife?
Mr. Mc:Cullen prefers his toffees
with the wrappers untouched.
But a horse is a damn sight easier
to ride if it's been broken in.
Hey.
Boss.
What about Bully?
He didn't make it. The gorge.
We lost some supplies, too.
We've lost too many lives
in that pass.
We'll say prayers
for him Sunday.
Uh, send the Jameson brothers for
the supplies in the morning.
Bertie? I think
these ladies need a drink.
RUSSELL: Aye.
So, what do you cost me?
No!
You don't like my money?
That's not what I said.
You don't like me? Actually,
I do quite like you.
My money's good, Bertie!
I know that, Freckles.
But you heard the lady.
What the hell
kind of a place is this?
I've got good money to spend
here, for Christ's sakes!
That's the last help
you'll get from me.
From now on, you'll fight
them off yourself.
Here. On the house.
Help you to relax.
Maybe loosen you up
a little.
I don't think so.
Dangerous out there,
pflncess.
Mr. McCullen doesn't like his
ladies getting into trouble,
losing their looks now.
Oh.
Wouldn't mind us getting a bit
of fresh air, now, would he?
Got a window in my room. All the
fresh air you need, Charlotte.
"Charlotte."
It's the kind of name
you just wanna
wrap your mouth around,
now, isn't it?
First onstage work you've ever
done in your life, eh, princess?
So, what's he up to,
this McCullen?
That's "Mr. McCullen"
to you.
And what he's up to is
making a life for himself
after all he's been through.
Losing his wife and his
child and all that he had.
Some folk would simply fall to pieces.
Others stand up,
they look to the future.
That's what your man's done.
He's got some big plans for Goldtown.
Some grand old plans.
Right. It's time for work.
Michael? Get those
fucking chairs down.
Right, gentlemen.
The house is open.
£1 for the English rose
over there.
Just sitting there, doing
nothing the whole time.
£1 for a dance.
Yes, well, fair's fair. After
all, business is business.
£2.
£2. Any bets on £2?
Come on, Bertie. £3.
£3!
£4, Bertie.
I believe we have a winner.
(LAUGHS)
Oh, come on there, love. I'm the
luckiest bastard in the room.
Hey, make it
a fast one, boys.
(MUSIC PLAYING)
(YELLS) Don't do that!
(MUSIC STOPS)
I'm flush today, love.
I can pay extra.
That's enough!
It's just
a misunderstanding.
Bertie, give the man
a refund.
Will you play a slow one?
(SLOW MUSIC PLAYING)
You from England?
Oxfordshire.
Are you from the north?
(CHUCKLES) The north?
Yes, lam. And proud.
Do you have family there?
CHARLOTTE: I'm an only child.
So, what brought you here?
To Goldtown?
No, to the island.
My husband.
He was killed.
We try to make a life for
ourselves, but it's hard.
Happiness finds
a way, though.
I pray for it every night,
Mr. McCullen.
Joshua. Please.
Can I show you something?
MAN: Marry me.
I've got good diggings.
Just ask Bertie.
I'll give you six sons. You
won't find more decent than me.
Have you got a ring?
Come back when
you've got a ring.
That's Goldtown.
It's beautiful.
It's what I want home
to look like in a year.
Very ambitious.
Maybe.
But these men have left
their families behind.
They've endured
great hardship
to be masters of
their own destiny.
The least I can do is provide
them with what they need.
They can make a life.
Better than anywhere else.
Yes, I suppose that does make
me ambitious, doesn't it?
Yeah.
(CHUCKLES)
"Endured great hardship."
I don't think I ever understood
the meaning of those words.
What did you expect?
I don't know.
I expected everything
to be perfect.
(SINGING) When we went
Up to bed Hey ding dorum
When we went up to bed
We being young
When we went to bed
He looked like he was dead
Maids, when you're young
Never wed an old man
For he's got no faloorum
Fadidle di dorum
He's got no faloorum,
fadidle di day
He's got no faloorum
Just a fadidle di dorum
Maids, when you're young
Never wed an old man
For he's got no faloorum
Fadidle di dorum
He's got no faloorum
Fadidle di day
Just a fadidle di dorum
Maids, when you're young
Never wed an old man
(ALL CHEERING)
MAN: English Rose
has got Freckles!
MAN 2: Way to go, Freckles!
(ALL CHEERING)
They're gonna be so jealous of me.
So jealous.
Hey! You fellas are gonna
be so jealous! (LAUGHS)
Here.
There you go. Yeah. Drink.
Good boy.
Lie with me.
Shh. Don't pretend you know
what you're doing.
You're the best
of any damn whore
lever laid eyes on.
Yeah.
Thank you. There we go.
The guys are
gonna be so jealous.
(SNORING)
(FRECKLES SNORING)
I know you said
I'm not welcome.
I know you said to not come back...
I say no come back!
But I have the same
photograph as you.
This is my son!
This is my son.
He's here in Goldtown.
It's the same photograph.
It's the same as yours.
This is my baby, see. Here.
You have the same photograph
on your mantelpiece.
(SPEAKS OTHER LANGUAGE)
My son's photograph.
(IN ENGLISH)
She says she tree people.
Yes, tree people.
What's the tree people?
(SPEAKS OTHER LANGUAGE)
Tree people... A woman
beyond the tree people.
Where's the tree people?
The woman with baby.
Baby. I saw him.
Yes. Yes. My son has this.
Yes. Yes.
Bush. The tree people.
Baby through bush.
Through the bush. All right.
I'm looking for
a woman with a baby.
(SPEAKS OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH) Do you speak English?
English? Okay.
(CHICKEN SQUAWKS)
(GASPS)
Excuse me, do you
speak English? English?
MAN: Morning! Morning!
Yes.
You buy.
Ah, yes, yes. You buy.
No, no.
I'm looking for
a woman with this baby.
(SPEAKING CANTONESE)
(IN ENGLISH) I don't...
A woman with...
(SPEAKING CANTONESE)
(IN ENGLISH) You buy?
No! I need to find
a woman with a baby.
I need to find
the woman in this...
(SPEAKING CANTONESE)
(IN ENGLISH) You buy.
Okay.
(SPEAKING CANTONESE)
(IN ENGLISH) English?
Go up.
Woman, a baby.
There. Go.
Thank you! Thank you!
(BABY COOING)
(WOMAN YELLING)
(WOMAN YELLING
IN SPANISH)
He's mine!
(SPEAKING SPANISH)
(IN ENGLISH)
The mother is dead!
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
He's my son.
HUNTER:
That'll do now, princess.
You give that
little one back now.
You want to do this
the hard way?
(BABY CRYING)
(GASPS)
Why did you take my baby?
(GASPING)
(COUGHING)
(GROANS)
(GASPS)
(GROANING)
(SPEAKING CANTONESE)
(IN ENGLISH) You done good, Chiney.
Come here. (GRUNTS)
Joshua.Joshua.
Um...
Hunter has my son.
Uh, there's a lady...
Joshua.
Needs more milk.
You have absolutely no idea
who I am, do you?
Mrs. Lockton.
I had a dream
just like your husband.
I came to this country with a
promise from my government
that the land was as ripe
as the opportunity.
Everything I had,
I lost.
Just a lucky few,
likes of your husband,
prospered.
Thinking he was doing
the likes of me a favor.
So, I made
my own opportunity.
Now, that requires
investments. Still does.
So I'll be needing your
generosity a while yet.
You killed my husband.
He'd have done
the same.
He almost did.
You took my son.
He's such
a sweet boy, Charlotte.
Knows his own mind already.
You'll see.
I said,
needs more milk.
You can have Oxfordshire. And all the land.
And the house.
I know I can.
Thank you.
You and your son
could be safe here.
(CRIES)
I just want my son.
And that's what I'm saying.
You understand?
(WHISPERS)
That is what I am saying.
Just obey the rules.
You can go now.
(RAIN SPLATTERING)
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(FOOTSTEPS)
(ARTHUR CRYING IN DISTANCE)
(CRYING CONTINUES)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
RUSSELL: Charlotte?
Shh!
What in God's name
are you doing?
(YELLS)
Why would you do this? Why? I don't
understand. Don't you love him?
Of course I do.
I would die for my son.
And so you might.
Why won't you
let me see my son?
Oh, this isn't good for business, darling.
No good at all.
He's a bad man.
There's a lot of people owe
their lives to Mr. Mc:Cullen.
Why won't any of you
let me see my son?
I know nothing
about the lad.
But would you just be
a good girlie?
Mind your mouth,
and get back to your work?
(GUN COCKS)
I need your help.
McCullen has my son.
He killed my husband,
and he has my son.
Joshua?
FLAMENCO: Loco!
I'm not loco, Maria Theresa.
He has my son.
Well, I ain't seen no kid
around here.
CHARLOTTE: He's here
in this hotel.
He's in the room
in the corner,
but Mc:Cullen's watching me
all the time, so I can't move
unless he knows.
Can you help, please?
Can you help me?
Can you help me get the key?
The key to what?
The key to the rooms.
You're in there all the time
with the diggers.
You can help me get to him.
And then what would you do?
I'd take my son,
and I'd go.
HONEY: Yeah,
but we stay here.
And if what you say is right...
I am right.
HONEY: Then they'll know soon
enough that you needed help.
And it won't be long before
they work out who helped you.
We live here now, remember? We
found ourselves new stories here.
Please? Please?
Fred. (LAUGHS)
Fred! Let's to bed, Fred!
(INAUDIBLE)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
(KNOCKS)
I like your hair down.
When I lost my family,
I cursed the heavens.
When I took your son,
I cursed myself.
But then I saw you.
You'd come for him.
To me.
You're too beautiful
for makeup.
We all want another's
heartbeat against our own.
(GRUNTS)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
Uh, gentlemen, gentlemen. We
have a very special treat.
Flamenco and I have prepared
something very special for you.
(MEN CHEERING AND WHISTLING)
(ARTHUR FUSSING)
I always knew you were
gonna be trouble.
(MEN CHEERING)
Jesus Christ.
(PANTING)
(ARTHUR FUSSING)
Put these on.
(INDISTINCT CHATTER)
You just don't listen,
do you?
(GRUNTS)
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(CHOKING)
You gonna die, bitch!
You gonna die!
(CHOKING)
(GRUNTING)
Die, bitch.
(GRUNTS)
(CHOKING)
Charlotte!
HUNTER: I'm gonna kill you.
(GRUNTING)
(YELLS)
(HUNTER GRUNTING)
I'll kill you!
(ARTHUR CRYING)
Goddamn bitch!
(GUNSHOT)
You can't outrun me!
(PEOPLE YELLING)
Shut up or you're next!
Where are you, girl?
What are you looking at?
I'm gonna find you.
Think I can't find you?
You can outrun me?
Huh?
Where are you
gonna run to, huh?
All the way
back to England?
I can smell you!
(GUNSHOT)
(GASPS)
(GROANING)
(CHARLOTTE WHIMPERING)
You think about
what's gonna happen
to that little one
when you die.
That's the last thought that's gonna
go through your head, sweetheart.
(GASPS)
(CHANTING IN OTHER LANGUAGE)
(THUD5)
(ARTHUR COOING)
(GROANS)
(SPEAKS OTHER LANGUAGE)
(GASPING)
(BULLET CLATTERS)
(IN ENGLISH)
Do you have family?
Once.
Killed.
(SPEAKS OTHER LANGUAGE)
(IN ENGLISH)
I was fishing.
They came from the north, and
they killed the whole village.
The English?
No. Maori.
Maori with muskets.
Where will you go? Home?
I don't know.
(GUNSHOT)
(HORSE WHINNIES)
(GROANS)
(ARTHUR CRYING)
(PANTING)
It's not really your world,
is it, Charlotte?
What was it you said?
Oh, yeah, that's right.
You expect everything
to be perfect.
Well, that's the thing,
isn't it?
It's not.
(ARTHUR FUSSING)
You need protecting in this world.
David knew that.
So do I.
Come on.
(CHARLOTTE GRUNTS)
(ARTHUR CRYING)
Put my son down.
Oh, come on, Charlotte.
Put him down.
Come on, look.
He's happy in my arms.
Can't you see? Look.
When you came to me, you don't
think that was destiny?
Put him down.
All right,
I'll tell you what.
I'm gonna count to three. Right?
Put it down. Life goes on.
Please.
Drop the gun.
No.
One... I mean it.
(GUN CLICKS)
Oh, Charlotte.
Thank you.
(GROANS)
(ARTHUR CRYING)
(GRUNTS)
(GUNSHOT)